Yoelvis Mulen

Senior Software Engineer





I have over 13 years of experience in developing software, I studied computer engineering several years ago and have worked on various projects using C++, PHP, C#, JavaScript, and other programming languages. Currently, I work as a Senior Full-Stack Engineer and Team Lead mainly using technologies like TypeScript, React.js, Node.js and AWS.

I have been working with clients from the United States for more than 7 years, with colleagues from various nationalities. I like the teamwork using agile methodologies focused on delivering results in the shortest possible time and with great quality, clean code, using the appropriate design patterns, and testing.

I am passionate about sharing my knowledge with the community, I am a teacher in an academy where I teach front-end and back-end courses focused on JavaScript technologies (React, Nodejs, MongoDB, Express, etc.). In addition, I actively participate as a **speaker** in meetups and events. I also have my YouTube channel where I share content about software development (https://www.youtube.com/yoelvism).

I am committed and focused on my work, I place great value on professional ethics and teamwork. I am interested in continuing to improve myself every day, face new challenges, and help others achieve their goals.



Experience

Dec/2020 -**Present** Remote

Constellation Agency

Senior Software Engineer and Team Leader.

I work as a Senior Full-Stack Engineer in the product "Alexia", which is a SaaS used by large, medium and small companies, especially in the automotive industry for handling large-scale advertisements.

- Development of a new version of the interface and the back-end of the product using React.js, TypeScript, Cypress, Node.js, Serverless and the AWS infrastructure (among other technologies).
- Lead a team of developers, PM, and QAs, helping them grow and organizing the work.

Skills: TypeScript, React.js, Redux, React-Query, Cypress, Node.js, AWS, Serverless, Docker,

Jun/2020 -Present Uruguay

Hack Academy

Back-End and Front-End Teacher

Teacher for the Back-End (Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Socket.io) and Front-End (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and React Native) courses.

Oct/2018 -Present Remote

Modus Create

Senior Full Stack Developer.

Working for important companies located in the United Stated, especially in the educational field, helping millions of users (staff, universities, highschools, educators, students) to improve college and career planning, admissions and enrollment management, student success and advising.

Skills: React.js, Redux, Node.js, AWS, Docker, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, GraphQL. Scrum.

Jan/2016 – Oct/2018 Montevideo.

Uruguay

Endava

Senior Software Engineer.

Full Stack developer for US companies leaders in the medical and real estate fields.

- Design and develop a high-performance reports system for CoStar.
- Implemented new modules for the platform of a leading US corporation medical services platform.
- Use of Scrum as the Agile framework for software development.

Skills: .Net, React, Node.js, Git, Scrum.

Sep/2015 – Jan/2016 Montevideo,

Uruguay

ATOS

Software Developer.

Development and support of an important project for the Social Security Bank of Uruguay.

Skills: C#, ASP.NET, Visual Basic, Oracle, Visual Studio, Scrum.

2012 - 2014

Havana, Cuba

E-Government Center

Web developer.

Developer in the "Automated Management System for the Cuban People's Courts" project (SIGTPC).

Implementation and testing of various Use Cases of the Criminal, Common and Economic matters; also implemented several useful features for the project architecture.

Skills: Symfony 2, HTML5, Bootstrap, PHP, JQuery, Subversion, PostgreSQL, Netbeans, RUP.

2011 - 2012

Industrial Computing Center

Havana, Web developer.
Cuba

Development of the project cycle life (Modeling, Requirements, Analysis and Design, Implementation and Testing) of the "Monte Carlo Simulation Module" for the project "Integrated Reliability System".

Skills: Java, JavaScript, Eclipse, Visual Paradigm, RUP.

2010 - 2011

Cubans Health Ministry

Táchira, Venezuela Software support.

Deployment and support of the "GalenLab" software in an "Integral Diagnostic Center" (IDC) of Táchira in Venezuela.

Manage computer networks in the IDC.

2008 - 2010

Industrial Computing Center

Havana, Cuba Software developer.

Development and support of the data collector module "Garbage Collector" in the "SCADA" project, developed for the Venezuelan oil and natural gas company "PDVSA".

Skills: C++, PostgreSQL, Eclipse, Boost.



Education

2007 - 2012 Havana, Cuba **Degree: Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering**

University of Informatics Sciences.

Main subjects received: Programming, Databases, Software Engineering, Software Management, e-Commerce, and English.

An advanced student with outstanding grades and active participation in real projects and programming contests.



 MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional.

Microsoft.

December 2016.

• Certified Scrum Developer

Kleer | Agile Coaching & Training
October 2016.

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Amazon
December 2019



Languages

Spanish: Native.

• English: Full professional proficiency.



Contact details

Address: Montevideo, UruguayEmail: yoelvismulen@gmail.com

• Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yoelvismulen/en

GitHub: https://github.com/ymulenllTwitter: https://twitter.com/ymulenll